<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Proposals by E.L. to raise one million three hundred thousand pounds. A general tax for five years to be laid on all measures, wett and dry, long measures, scales and stilliards, wherewith any sort of merchandize or commodity is sold or exchanged. ...</title>
            <author>E. L.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B25550</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L16</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.6[33]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224800</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99885665</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99885665</idno>
            <idno type="VID">201584</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B25550)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 201584)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C25:3[34])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Proposals by E.L. to raise one million three hundred thousand pounds. A general tax for five years to be laid on all measures, wett and dry, long measures, scales and stilliards, wherewith any sort of merchandize or commodity is sold or exchanged. ...</title>
                  <author>E. L.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Title from caption and opening lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Taxation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Mensuration --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:201584:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>Propoſals by <hi>E. L.</hi> to raiſe One Million Three Hundred Thouſand Pounds.</head>
            <p>A General Tax for five Years to be laid on all Meaſures, Wett and Dry, Long Meaſures, Scales, and Stilliards, wherewith any ſort of Merchandize or Commodity is ſold or exchanged.</p>
            <p>Each of theſe to be ſtampt every Year once, and pay as underneath for each Stamp.</p>
            <p>The Wett Meaſures as by a computation taken out of the Exciſe Office, will amount to 100000 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This is now practiſed in ſome Foreign parts.
<table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The Dry and Long Meaſures, Scales and Stilliards, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at an eaſy computation is</cell>
                     <cell>100000 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi>
                     </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The Traders not ſelling by Weights and Meaſures, and Mills, is computed at</cell>
                     <cell>60000 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi>
                     </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>12 <hi>d.</hi> For each Flaggon, Pott, Mugg, Tankard, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> not Silver, containing Two Penny<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth of Ale or Beer; or any other Liquor not exceeding Six-pence <hi>per</hi> Quart, or not hereafter named.</p>
            <p>6 <hi>d.</hi> For each Pint or leſſer Meaſure, containing one Pennyworth of <hi>Ditto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>2 <hi>s.</hi> For each Flaggon, Pottle, Gallon, containing four Pennyworth of <hi>Ditto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>3 <hi>s.</hi> For each Tankard, Bowl, or Pott, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of Silver, containing two Pennyworth of <hi>Ditto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>1 <hi>s. 6 d.</hi> For each Pint, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of Silver, containing one Pennyworth of <hi>Ditto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>5 <hi>s.</hi> For each double Tankard, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of Silver, containing more than two Pennyworth of <hi>Ditto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>2 <hi>s.</hi> For each Quart Pott, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> wherein Wine, Brandy, or any other Spirit, Oyl, Vinegar, Mum, or any other Liquor, above Six-pence <hi>per</hi> Quart, is ſold.</p>
            <p>1 <hi>s.</hi> For each Pint, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of <hi>Ditto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>6 <hi>d.</hi> For each leſſer Meaſure.</p>
            <p>5 <hi>s.</hi> For each Pottle, Gallon, or larger Meaſure, containing <hi>Ditto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>For all Silver Tankards, ſingle and double, as above.</p>
            <p>5 <hi>s.</hi> For each Yard or Ell, or if mark'd on the Compter or elſewhere.</p>
            <p>10 <hi>s.</hi> For each Wollen drapers Yard.</p>
            <p>Each Linnen Draper, or any one that ſelleth Linnens, ſhall be obliged to have both Yard and Ell.</p>
            <p>All dealers Whole-Sale, ſhall be obliged to have Yards or Ells thus Stampt.</p>
            <p>5 <hi>s.</hi> For each Buſhel or larger Meaſure.</p>
            <p>2 <hi>s. 6 d.</hi> For each half Buſhel.</p>
            <p>1 <hi>s.</hi> For each Peck.</p>
            <p>6 <hi>d.</hi> For each leſſer Dry Meaſure.</p>
            <p>5 <hi>s.</hi> For each Hoſtlers Peck. 2 <hi>s. 6 d.</hi> each half Peck, and 1 <hi>s.</hi> for each Quarter of a Peck.</p>
            <p>Each Inn or Houſe, where Horſe are entertained, ſhall be obliged to have theſe three Meaſures, or pay the Forfeiture, as underneath, for want of any of them.</p>
            <p>5 <hi>s.</hi> For each pair of Scales or Stilliards held up by the hand when uſed.</p>
            <p>10 <hi>s.</hi> For each pair of <hi>Ditto</hi> faſtned above when uſed.</p>
            <p>All Manners of Earthen Ware, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall have a Lidd of Pewter, or the like Metal, ſo as they may be Stampt.</p>
            <p>If any ſell Bottle Ale or Beer, they ſhall be obliged to rack it off into one of theſe ſtampt Meaſures. If not, to forfeit as underneath.</p>
            <p>That no Vintner or Wine Seller, ſhall ſell Wine in Bottles, or Flasks by Retail, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept the Oyl be taken off in preſence of the Buyers. Mum and all other Liquors, as Ale and Beer, upon the like forfeiture as underneath.</p>
            <p>If any Perſon ſhall buy, ſell, exchange, or barter, with any Meaſure, Scale or Stilliard, not ſtampt, ſhall pay for the firſt offence 10 <hi>l.</hi> for every offence after 20 <hi>l.</hi> half to be paid to the Informer, the other half to the King.</p>
            <p>If any Perſon ſhall buy, ſell, exchange or barter with any Meaſure, Scale or Stilliard not his own, he ſhall pay the ſaid forfeiture; ſo ſhall the Lender as well as the Borrower.</p>
            <p>If any Perſon preſume to counterfeit, or put a falſe Stamp upon any Meaſure, Scale, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> he ſhall pay 50 <hi>l.</hi> Be impriſoned a Year, or loſe his Ears, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That a Tax be granted on all Mills for five years.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>20 <hi>s. per Ann.</hi> For each Water-Wheel, whether for Corn, Fullers, Paper, or other uſe, and the ſame for each Horſe-Mill, Wind-Mill, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That each Trader that neither ſells by Weight nor Meaſure, ſhall pay 10 <hi>S. per Annum.</hi> Such as theſe, <hi>Atturnys, Scriveners, Shoomakers, Glaziers, Glovers, Cutlers, Stationers, Bookſellers, Furriers, Pin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, Needlemakers, Coopers, Turners, Combmakers Writing-Maſters, School-Maſters, Dancing-Maſters, Fencing-Maſters, Taylers, Painters, Pattinmakers, Farriers, Poulterers, Potters, Barbers, Wigmakers, Cabinet-Makers, Fiſhmongers, Joyners, Carpenters, Spurriers, Gilders, Fletchers, Maſons,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Theſe Taxes to be put into the Exciſe Office, and will be but very little trouble. The General Stamping being but once a Year.</p>
            <p>The Charge in Collecting, will amount to about 7000 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> allowing as follows, one Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner to be added, 20 <hi>l.</hi> to each Collector, 10 <hi>l.</hi> to each Superviſor, 5 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> to each Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger, and proportionably of the reſt.</p>
            <p>No Meaſure to be Stampt but in preſence of Collector, Superviſor and Gager, or two at the leaſt.</p>
            <p>It is to be noted, that the firſt Years Revenue may be Collected in two Months, after this ſhall be enacted; or Three Months at moſt.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
